<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Real Estate Update E-newsletter</title>
    <link>http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Real_Estate_Market_News.html</link>
    <description>This monthly update is written by me with the most interesting, newsworthy happenings in real estate.  From the specifics of the Denver market to national trends, I try to cover every thing you should know about what’s occurring in the industry.  Each month features articles on everything from tips to helping sellers before they list, observations on the home buying front as well as industry news that affects everyone, even those not currently thinking about a real estate move- there is something in it for everyone.&lt;br/&gt;To receive this newsletter, please email Elizabeth at Elizabeth@DenverRealEstate.com</description>
    <generator>iWeb 3.0.4</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Real_Estate_Market_News_files/IMG_2697.jpg</url>
      <title>Real Estate Update E-newsletter</title>
      <link>http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Real_Estate_Market_News.html</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>June 2012 Real Estate Update</title>
      <link>http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/6/6_June_2012_Real_Estate_Update.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">c64a46b6-3119-456c-aa45-5289d095e33d</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 6 Jun 2012 17:31:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/6/6_June_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/IMG_0774.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Media/object004_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:183px; height:137px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;First Annual Your Neighborhood Experts Washington Park Garage Sale&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Need to get rid of stuff?  Need to add a few more sweet pieces of furniture?  Come join me and my team for our first annual garage sale in a number of homes across Washington Park- 12 so far!  We’ve got a number of homes participating and are looking for more, so whatever you do, block off June 23rd from 9-2 for some shopping!  Check out my team website for more details:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonparkresidences.com/&quot;&gt;www.washingtonparkresidences.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;House Maintenance To-Do's&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As we get into June, home maintenance projects begin to re-appear on many people’s calendars.  At the request of some clients, I’ve decided to write my own version of a home maintenance to do list.  These are some suggestions that I thought of today and I hope it helps you all!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Day of Closing&lt;br/&gt;Call Excel to transfer utilities&lt;br/&gt;Water/Sewer is automatically transferred by title company&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;When You Move In&lt;br/&gt;Paint before you move in any furniture!&lt;br/&gt;Rekey or Change your locks&lt;br/&gt;Set up Alarm System&lt;br/&gt;Set up Phone, Internet, TV&lt;br/&gt;Change your mailing address with post office and all of your bills and friends!!&lt;br/&gt;Set up electronic payment of mortgage&lt;br/&gt;Set up house account for joint home purchases&lt;br/&gt;Get a safety deposit box for house documents&lt;br/&gt;Change Garage Door Opener Code&lt;br/&gt;Set up iPhone alarms on garbage, recycling and street sweeping&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Every 3 Months:&lt;br/&gt;Change/Clean your furnace Filter&lt;br/&gt;Use self cleaning oven feature&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Every Year:&lt;br/&gt;Service your Furnace and Air Conditioning System&lt;br/&gt;Clean your sewer line&lt;br/&gt;Check batteries in smoke/CO2 detectors&lt;br/&gt;Renew Alarm with City of Denver&lt;br/&gt;Make sure garage door safety reverse is functioning&lt;br/&gt;Ensure all GFCI outlets are working&lt;br/&gt;Clean fridge coils&lt;br/&gt;Ensure Vent for Dryer is clear&lt;br/&gt;Re-caulk any tubs, sinks where seal is broken&lt;br/&gt;Clean out window wells in basement&lt;br/&gt;Clean dishwasher food filter&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Every October 15th&lt;br/&gt;Winterize your sprinkler system&lt;br/&gt;Check weather stripping, window and door seal&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Every May 15th&lt;br/&gt;Turn on your sprinkler system&lt;br/&gt;Aerate the lawn&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Every 3-5 Years&lt;br/&gt;Clean Windows&lt;br/&gt;Clean out Gutters&lt;br/&gt;Check Trim for painting&lt;br/&gt;Clean your air ducts&lt;br/&gt;Clean Chimneys&lt;br/&gt;Drain water heater to remove sediment (usually 1-2 gallons)&lt;br/&gt;Trim trees&lt;br/&gt;Clean Carpet</description>
      <enclosure url="http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/6/6_June_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/IMG_0774.jpg" length="214637" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>May 2012 Real Estate Update</title>
      <link>http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/5/10_May_2012_Real_Estate_Update.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">237afd55-72a1-4202-9dcf-70a2d41c2f26</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 10:45:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/5/10_May_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/IMG_0612.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Media/object005_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:183px; height:137px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What?  A Bidding War you say?&lt;br/&gt;The market has moved so fast in the last month its hard for both buyers and sellers to believe.  The role of the agent managing the expectations and disappointments of this process can have added challenges.  Back in the days of the slower market, it used to be that maximizing your clients best possible price allowed most realtors to be hero’s.  You could get unbelievable prices on a home for your buyer, and just getting something sold at all was a minor victory in a slow moving market.  Today, most brokers will tell you that keeping the deal together is a very challenging process.  and getting your client the house is often the best victory you can hope for.  Denver is a little ahead of this curve and not all cities are experiences our fast pace, but I suspect that many will soon.  Have a good solid plan of attack if you’re thinking about buying soon- and that includes bringing a checkbook with you- many of these houses are going under contract within hours of hitting the MLS!  If you’re thinking about selling- you should probably do it NOW.  As in, right now.  Seriously....&lt;br/&gt;Meet my Team!&lt;br/&gt;Check out a new tab at the top of my website: Your Neighborhood Experts.  This is a team project I’m working on with two incredible real estate agents that I work with regularly, Pam Coakley and Catherine Carpenter!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;First Quarter Sales Data- How is your Neighborhood Doing this year?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Real Estate Quiz&lt;br/&gt;Sent by a great friend in California, I thought this was something you might enjoy from the Wall Street Journal:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.wsj.com/quiz/index.php?uid=challenge120427&amp;type=realestate&amp;mod=e2tw&quot;&gt;How Well do you Know Luxury Real Estate?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Denver is #2 in Nation for Quick Sales!&lt;br/&gt;The Denver Post has some great information on how our real estate environment has changed in the last few months.  If you’d like a little light reading, check out this article:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.denverpost.com/business/ci_20429074/denver-housing-market-second-nation-quick-sales?source=email&quot;&gt;Denver Post on Real Estate Sales&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Financing a Condo, Here I go again...&lt;br/&gt;Selling or buying a condominium has added challenges with restrictions on the kind of financing available.  However, never has it been harder for sellers to sell when federal guidelines often punish small developments and prevent any buyer from getting a loan.  If, for example, you live in a small building and one person owns even 2 units- this might make even a traditional conventional loan a virtual impossibility if one owner has a larger than 10-20% share in the building.  As these types of buildings are pervasive around Denver, I’m adopting new strategies to ensure that the perfect buyer actually CAN buyer your unit.  It all begins and ends with a condo questionnaire.  Making sure this document is reviewed by a lender can tell you a lot about your property and I believe it now falls on agents to add this step to the initial listing process.  Never before has this raised as many problems as it does now, but this tiny step can save you months of headaches!&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/5/10_May_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/IMG_0612.jpg" length="153128" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>April 2012 Real Estate Update</title>
      <link>http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/3/7_April_2012_Real_Estate_Update.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">90810203-2418-41ab-901f-716b430f00a4</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 7 Mar 2012 13:01:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/3/7_April_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/724521_800x600.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Media/object000_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:183px; height:137px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Darling New Congress Park Condo Listing&lt;br/&gt;Check out this amazing condo featured above- it’s a steal of a deal at $160,000 for 2 beds, 1 bath, reserved parking and 948 square feet on one of the best blocks in the city: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spotlighthometours.com/tours/tour.php?&amp;tourid=32688&quot;&gt;1149 Columbine Photo Tour&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The New Real Estate Market&lt;br/&gt;Multiple Offers?  Back Up Offers?  Selling above asking price?  It’s happening, people.  No one has ever seen a market turn so suddenly and there’s good news on both sides.  For sellers, well priced, well staged homes are selling often in a matter of days and increasingly close to or even above the asking price.  For buyers, you’re all very knowledgeable about value in this market, and that’s why the best priced properties are selling fast- but they are also often appraising above that!   You’re getting the value on two ends- one- prices are still low in Denver and two- you’ve got a great mortgage rate.  Even sellers who may sell  at a loss are starting to list their homes so they can recover any lost profit back on their next home.  This is a unique market and one we hope will continue through the summer.   It’s great to see a healthy and balanced real estate market in Denver!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Property Insurance- New Problems&lt;br/&gt;Most people hear me say at some point, “Be sure to get a quote for your homeowner’s insurance by (insert date).”  I know with the zillion things you’re already doing, this can easily fall to the back burner.  However, in the ever-changing world of real estate, this deadline is an important one.  Insurance companies are starting to really analyze homes and make sure claims don’t pop up early on.  What this means is that the roof that your inspector said might be a problem- might actually jeopardize your insurance- so get it checked out early in the deal!&lt;br/&gt;Obamacare Tax on the Sale of Real Estate&lt;br/&gt;There’s a lot of misinformation going around about the tax described in the Obamacare bill that will come from the sale of real estate.  The biggest thing to note is that it’s not across the board and only a small few will be eligible to pay  The law itself stipulates that in 2013, a 3.8% tax will be added on top of the capital gains tax if:&lt;br/&gt;	1.	 You jointly make more than $250,000 a year as a couple and the tax would only be applied to the portion of the next gain that is itself taxable.  You are allowed to make a certain amount of profit, so this is only on your taxable gain.&lt;br/&gt;	2.	The sale of second homes&lt;br/&gt;Please call me or your CPA for further details, but sellers, don’t worry- with real estate trending where it is, you’ll still probably want to sell your house anyways in 2013!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Happy Spring!&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/3/7_April_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/724521_800x600.jpg" length="151908" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>March 2012 Real Estate Update</title>
      <link>http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/3/1_March_2012_Real_Estate_Update.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">04d393fd-98e1-49c5-9954-fe5dbc91cd2d</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 1 Mar 2012 16:34:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/3/1_March_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/IMG_0468.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Media/object003_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:182px; height:184px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Update on Union Station&lt;br/&gt;I was fortunate a few weeks ago to have the opportunity to meet with the governor and the principal developer of the project.  In short, it’s going to completely change our city in an incredible.  Denver is unique in that it has an enormous amount of undeveloped land in such a desirable location.  Expect in the next few years to see thousands of new condos and apartments (you’ll hear my thoughts on that in a later missive), shopping and an incredible way for commuters to get to downtown. (I hope it helps I-25 commuter traffic!)  Take a look at their latest video to see their vision for the future:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unionstationdenver.com/&quot;&gt;Union Station Development Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To List or Not to List?  That is the question...&lt;br/&gt;The market is changing at a dramatic pace.  Wow, in the last two weeks, we’ve seen something we haven’t in the marketplace in years: urgency!  That’s right, buyers, you had better put in an offer now if you like a place, because bidding wars are happening on desirable places all over the city.  Sellers, with low inventory like we’re seeing, if you price well and show well, you’re very likely to see offers coming in quickly!  To put it in perspective, one of the centralized call centers to set showings was so busy over the past weekend, you couldn’t get through to set a showing for HOURS.  Welcome back real estate market, I’ve missed you!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Market Data:&lt;br/&gt;For your number crunchers out there, here’s the cold hard facts.  In January, the number of unsold homes plumbed bu 41.6% from January 2011.  This is record drop year-over-year for the denver market.  What that means, by the end of January there were only about 10,400 homes for sale anywhere in the city.  This is what has singlehandedly driven the market in a different direction and compelled buyers to make their moves as the inventory kept moving so quickly.  The data I’ll have next month should provide a lot of good news for the real estate industry in Denver.  Oh, and did I mention that interest rates still keep dropping below 4%? &lt;br/&gt;Thank you, Warren Buffet&lt;br/&gt;I know you hear it from me all the time, so perhaps the words of Warren Buffet will add weight to what I am always saying.  He was quoted as telling CNBC that houses are “an attractive investment” and he’d buy more if he could manage them effectively.  Word to the wise....&lt;br/&gt;WARNING: SCAM&lt;br/&gt;A scam has appeared in Denver whereby a few weeks or months after you purchase your home, you’ll get a letter stating you need to get a warranty deed and are directed to send a check to a company resembling the county of Denver.  It’s a scam.  Don’t do it.  Call me if you get this letter.</description>
      <enclosure url="http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/3/1_March_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/IMG_0468.jpg" length="195826" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>January/February 2012 Real Estate Update</title>
      <link>http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/1/2_January_February_2012_Real_Estate_Update.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">241239de-996e-4add-91c8-58121c11a0dd</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 2 Jan 2012 22:25:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/1/2_January_February_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/Kentwood.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Media/object004_1.png&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:183px; height:137px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My Move to Kentwood Real Estate&lt;br/&gt;This month marks my professional move over to Kentwood Real Estate.  I am so excited to join their Cherry Creek office and their exceptionally talented group of real estate brokers.  Kentwood offers one of the strongest, most respected names in Denver Real Estate.  We’ve also officially partnered with Christie’s International Realty to offer our clients the finest marketing opportunities.  Although I will deeply miss many incredible brokers and friends at Sotheby’s, I look forward to my new venture and the many new resources  I will be able to offer my clients. &lt;br/&gt;My new contact information is as follows:&lt;br/&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Elizabeth@DenverRealEstate.com/&quot;&gt;Elizabeth@DenverRealEstate.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;New Work Address: 44 Cook St, 9th Floor, Denver, CO.  My cell phone is still 303.501.3337.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Sales Statistics for 2011&lt;br/&gt;Here’s all you need to know about your neighborhood:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Condos&lt;br/&gt;When buying a condo, realtor’s have a much tougher job for their clients than ever before.  This is in part due to the mountains of information they must review to ensure the condo development has FHA approval.  Even if you don’t get an FHA loan, this will certainly affect your ability to sell down the road, so make sure you know ALL the facts before buying a condo.  I can help with that : )  For more information about this, check out this Denver Post article: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.denverpost.com/search/ci_19789026&quot;&gt;Article on FHA Approval and Condos&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The Houses and Buildings of Peru&lt;br/&gt;As many of you know, I took a trip to Peru in November of this year and I wanted to share a few pictures I took.  The real estate broker in me couldn’t stop noticing the housing.  For more pictures of the trip, please check out my facebook page.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://www.elizabethsacerdoti.com/ElizabethSacerdoti.com/Real_Estate_Market_News/Entries/2012/1/2_January_February_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/Kentwood.png" length="16634" type="image/png"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
