<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:51:54 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;November Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_November_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Monday, November 1, 2010</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>November Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;News for Fuller Sothebys!&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;First, we just opened a &lt;b&gt;new office in Writer&#x2019;s Square&lt;/b&gt; in downtown Denver. &#xA0;We&#x2019;re one of only a handful of real estate companies that has actually been expanding this year. &#xA0;I will remain in our Cherry Creek office, but check out our new space downtown!&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Frequent Traveller? &lt;/b&gt;&#xA0;CLEAR (&lt;a href="http://www.clearme.com/"&gt;www.clearme.com&lt;/a&gt;), the first and only biometric-based Registered Traveler program for airport security, has commenced in-person enrollment at select Fuller Sotheby&#x2019;s International Realty locations and, starting in November, at the Cherry Creek Shopping Center. &#xA0;In Denver, new members may complete their enrollment at the Fuller Sotheby&#x2019;s Denver &#xA0;Tech Center office at 8400 E. Crescent Parkway, Suite 300, Greenwood Village. In Boulder, the enrollment center is near the 29th Street Mall, at 1500 28th Street. Hours of operation are Monday to Friday 9 AM through 6 PM.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Investment Suggestion: Buy a Vacation Renta&lt;/b&gt;l&#xD;I&#x2019;m going to go ahead and say it again: real estate is still a solid long term investment and it&#x2019;s never been a better time to buy. &#xA0;But how can you take advantage? &#xA0;Purchase a vacation home and rent it out to travelers. &#xA0;Rental properties in vacation markets tend to pay for themselves and you can enjoy the benefits while earning a profit. &#xA0;Many vacation markets have never had so much inventory, prices are unlikely to ever be better and interest rates are still unbeatable. Its also never been easier to rent out properties with websites like VRBO.com and craigslist drawing records visitors to their sites.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Latest News on the Foreclosure Situation&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;With the announcement of faulty &#x201C;robo-signing&#x201D; of foreclosure documents, many banks are temporarily freezing their foreclosures in order to make sure their paperwork is correct. &#xA0;What does this mean to you? &#xA0;A halt of new foreclosures from entering the market could provide an upswing in real estate as their will be fewer homes for sale. &#xA0;Long term, seeing these troubled properties through the market will be the only way to full heal the real estate industry, so we&#x2019;ve still got some time before the market is more fully balanced.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Best cities for trick or treating?&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;Zillow announced the top 20 cities for trick or treating based on walk score, population density, crime rates and home values. &#xA0;This year, Denver ranked 5th! &#xA0;The top four cities include Seattle, San Francisco, Portland and San Jose.</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
