<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:51:51 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;July Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_July_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Thursday, July 1, 2010</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>July Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Pets and Condos&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Good news to pet owners! It seems many property managers have begun to appreciate your dog. &#xA0;Many urban markets, Denver included, have reported seeing a substantial increase in pet-friendly condo and apartment developments and this is likely a trend that is here to stay. &#xA0;Denver is a great example of a city with a large young urbanite population that also has one of the highest levels of dog ownership per capita in the country. &#xA0;Although it is always strongly recommended to double and triple check that your dog is allowed in your condo (some communities will even stipulate weight limits or breed restrictions), it is becoming increasingly common for pets to live downtown with you. &#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Tax Credits: Two Extensions&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Colorado has a strong military presence and as a result, we often deal with families with a primary member serving overseas. &#xA0;If you're in that camp, then there is excellent news if you're currently looking for a home. &#xA0;Active duty military personnel have an extension to April 30, 2011 to have an accepted contract on a home to qualify for the $8,000 tax credit. Secondly, some of you have asked me about an extension to the existing home credit. &#xA0;Don't be misled, this doesn't affect you if you are still shopping for a home! &#xA0;On Tuesday, the House of Representatives voted to give buyers with a contract dated prior to April 30, 2010, a few more months to &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;close&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; on that home. &#xA0;The original credit forced you to close by June 30, the new one gives you until September 30th. &#xA0;This isn't going to affect very many people (estimated about 200,000), as you still must have been under contract by April 30, 2010, so disregard this if you've just started looking. &#xA0;This bill is clearly targeted to help homeowners whose closings have been delayed with bank owned properties by giving them (and their realtors) a few extra months to get the deal closed.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Summer Dilemna: To Rent or To Buy&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The main issue facing first time buyers this summer is the question over whether to buy or not to buy now that the tax credit has expired. &#xA0;For many, it seems that the question is easy- Interest rates are still unbelievably low, there's lots of inventory and prices are low, so why not buy? &#xA0;However, sometimes personal circumstances complicate these issues and many worry over the end of the tax credit (although on May 1st when the credit expired, a significant percentage of properties lowered their price well over $8,000). &#xA0;So, how do you determine if you really can afford the monthly payments and if you feel comfortable owning a home? &#xA0;The first place I tell people to start is speaking with a lender who should be able to tell you what your credit score looks like and help you determine whether or not you can get a monthly payment that feels comfortable and even commensurate with what you currently pay in rent. Secondly, talk to a CPA or accountant about the net affect on your overall taxes at the end of the year. &#xA0;For many, the tax advantages of having your mortgage interest deducted are significant. &#xA0;If you're waffling, the combination of some of these factors may provide enough financial incentive to make a move well worth your time. &#xA0;At the very least, if you've thought about it before, it's very worth your time to look into a move into real estate ownership.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;The Gulf Spill and Real Estate&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;The oil disaster in the gulf has affected thousands of jobs dependent upon fishing and tourist industries, among many others. &#xA0;There are many families out there that have recently gotten in trouble paying their mortgages due to losses in income. &#xA0;As a result, Freddie Mac and Fannie Mae have announced that mortgage servicers may provide some relief to borrowers who are unable to pay their loans due to financial hardship as a result of the spill. &#xA0;According to the information on their website,&#xA0;&lt;a href="http://www.freddiemac.com/"&gt;www.freddiemac.com&lt;/a&gt;, "Freddie Mac&#x2019;s forbearance policies give servicers the discretion to suspend a borrower&#x2019;s mortgage payments for up to three months or reduce payments for up to six months. Servicers may recommend forbearance for up to twelve months, based on the borrower&#x2019;s individual circumstances. " &#xA0;Borrowers are asked to speak directly with their loan provider to inquire about this information, so if you know someone affected significantly by the spill, let them know!</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
