<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:52:11 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;March Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_March_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="296px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Thursday, March 1, 2012</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>March 2012 Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Update on Union Station&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;I was fortunate a few weeks ago to have the opportunity to meet with the governor and the principal developer of the project.  In short, it&#x2019;s going to completely change our city in an incredible.  Denver is unique in that it has an enormous amount of undeveloped land in such a desirable location.  Expect in the next few years to see thousands of new condos and apartments (you&#x2019;ll hear my thoughts on that in a later missive), shopping and an incredible way for commuters to get to downtown. (I hope it helps I-25 commuter traffic!)  Take a look at their latest video to see their vision for the future:&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.unionstationdenver.com/"&gt;Union Station Development Video&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;To List or Not to List?  That is the question...&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The market is changing at a dramatic pace.  Wow, in the last two weeks, we&#x2019;ve seen something we haven&#x2019;t in the marketplace in years: urgency!  That&#x2019;s right, buyers, you had better put in an offer now if you like a place, because bidding wars are happening on desirable places all over the city.  Sellers, with low inventory like we&#x2019;re seeing, if you price well and show well, you&#x2019;re very likely to see offers coming in quickly!  To put it in perspective, one of the centralized call centers to set showings was so busy over the past weekend, you couldn&#x2019;t get through to set a showing for HOURS.  Welcome back real estate market, I&#x2019;ve missed you!&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;The Market Data:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;For your number crunchers out there, here&#x2019;s the cold hard facts.  In January, the number of unsold homes plumbed bu 41.6% from January 2011.  This is record drop year-over-year for the denver market.  What that means, by the end of January there were only about 10,400 homes for sale anywhere in the city.  This is what has singlehandedly driven the market in a different direction and compelled buyers to make their moves as the inventory kept moving so quickly.  The data I&#x2019;ll have next month should provide a lot of good news for the real estate industry in Denver.  Oh, and did I mention that interest rates still keep dropping below 4%? &#xD;&lt;b&gt;Thank you, Warren Buffet&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;I know you hear it from me all the time, so perhaps the words of Warren Buffet will add weight to what I am always saying.  He was quoted as telling CNBC that houses are &#x201C;an attractive investment&#x201D; and he&#x2019;d buy more if he could manage them effectively.  Word to the wise....&#xD;&lt;b&gt;WARNING: SCAM&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;A scam has appeared in Denver whereby a few weeks or months after you purchase your home, you&#x2019;ll get a letter stating you need to get a warranty deed and are directed to send a check to a company resembling the county of Denver.  It&#x2019;s a scam.  Don&#x2019;t do it.  Call me if you get this letter.</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
