<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:52:12 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;April Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="7_April_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Monday, April 2nd, 2012</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>April 2012 Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Darling New Congress Park Condo Listing&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Check out this amazing condo featured above- it&#x2019;s a steal of a deal at $160,000 for 2 beds, 1 bath, reserved parking and 948 square feet on one of the best blocks in the city: &lt;a href="http://www.spotlighthometours.com/tours/tour.php?&amp;tourid=32688"&gt;1149 Columbine Photo Tour&#xD;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;The New Real Estate Market&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Multiple Offers?  Back Up Offers?  Selling above asking price?  It&#x2019;s happening, people.  No one has ever seen a market turn so suddenly and there&#x2019;s good news on both sides.  For sellers, well priced, well staged homes are selling often in a matter of days and increasingly close to or even above the asking price.  For buyers, you&#x2019;re all very knowledgeable about value in this market, and that&#x2019;s why the best priced properties are selling fast- but they are also often appraising above that!   You&#x2019;re getting the value on two ends- one- prices are still low in Denver and two- you&#x2019;ve got a great mortgage rate.  Even sellers who may sell  at a loss are starting to list their homes so they can recover any lost profit back on their next home.  This is a unique market and one we hope will continue through the summer.   It&#x2019;s great to see a healthy and balanced real estate market in Denver!&#xD;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Property Insurance- New Problems&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Most people hear me say at some point, &#x201C;Be sure to get a quote for your homeowner&#x2019;s insurance by (insert date).&#x201D;  I know with the zillion things you&#x2019;re already doing, this can easily fall to the back burner.  However, in the ever-changing world of real estate, this deadline is an important one.  Insurance companies are starting to really analyze homes and make sure claims don&#x2019;t pop up early on.  What this means is that the roof that your inspector said might be a problem- might actually jeopardize your insurance- so get it checked out early in the deal!&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Obamacare Tax on the Sale of Real Estate&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;There&#x2019;s a lot of misinformation going around about the tax described in the Obamacare bill that will come from the sale of real estate.  The biggest thing to note is that it&#x2019;s not across the board and only a small few will be eligible to pay  The law itself stipulates that in 2013, a 3.8% tax will be added on top of the capital gains tax if:&#xD;	1.	 You jointly make more than $250,000 a year as a couple and the tax would only be applied to the portion of the next gain that is itself taxable.  You are allowed to make a certain amount of profit, so this is only on your taxable gain.&#xD;	2.	The sale of second homes&#xD;Please call me or your CPA for further details, but sellers, don&#x2019;t worry- with real estate trending where it is, you&#x2019;ll still probably want to sell your house anyways in 2013!&#xD;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Happy Spring!&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
