<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:52:09 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;November/December Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="9_November_December_2011_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Wednesday, November 9, 2011</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>November/December 2011 Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Above:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; New Park Hill Listing at &lt;a href="http://www.spotlighthometours.com/tours/tour.php?&amp;tourid=30358&amp;CFID=1148287&amp;CFTOKEN=26544694"&gt;2853 Bellaire Street, Denver, CO&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;What&#x2019;s your house worth today? &#xA0;Allow me to tell you!&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;Whether you&#x2019;re thinking about moving or not, it&#x2019;s never a bad idea to know what you&#x2019;re house is worth today. &#xA0;Many people are concerned that their home has fallen in value or are curious about how their home improvement projects have increased value since their purchased. &#xA0;I&#x2019;m happy to sit down with you or email you a full report on your home&#x2019;s value and the comparable solds in your neighborhood. &#xA0;Email or call me anytime and I can let you know where things stand. &#xA0;Knowledge is power and in this market, evaluating what a minor change might do to help out your real estate investment down the road may help your long term goals.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Who&#x2019;s Helping the US Housing Market? &#xA0;The World&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;CNN ran an interesting article a few days ago citing growing international investment in US properties. &#xA0;Because these sales have so dramatically helped places like South Florida, the senate is putting forth a bill that will actually grant US visas to investors who spend $500k or more on residential property. Last March, according to the National Association of Realtors, international buyers represented 8% of the total US sales- $82 billion in a 12 month period. &#xA0;This figure represents a 24% increase from the 12 months prior. &#xA0;Some markets, 25% of buyers are international. If the bill passes, we may well see a sharp rise in sales, especially in the major US markets. &#xA0;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Union Station Update!&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;The Denver Post has just reported two different proposals for the 19 acre Union Station redevelopment, slated to open in spring of 2014. &#xA0;The Downtown Denver Partnership recently hosted an event for realtors to see first hand what these changes will be.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Plan One:&lt;/b&gt; Union Station Neighborhood Co. - The train station will have a restaurant, a walk-thru food market, new waiting room amenities, an information kiosk and about 25,000 square feet of leasable office space.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Plan Two:&lt;/b&gt; Union Station Alliance - A boutique 130 room hotel, connected to the Oxford Hotel with additional restaurant and office space as well.&#xD;RTD will make a formal recommendation on one of these plans by the end of the month and the board will make a decision early next year. &#xA0;Stay tuned for more info on the future of downtown Denver!&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Mortgage Rates this week:&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;September Home Sales in Review:&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
