<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:51:47 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;February Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_February_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Monday, February 1, 2010</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>February Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;2009 In Review: The Denver Market&lt;/b&gt; &#xD;&#xD;In this month's E-Newsletter, I'm attaching a detailed look at the specific neighborhoods of Denver and how both the sales and the price per square foot changed between 2008 and 2009. Take a look at the attachment at the end of this newsletter for more information on how your neighborhood fared in 2009. &#xD;&#xD;From 2007 to 2008, the average home price in the Denver metro area decreased about 13%. Surprisingly, the comparison between 2008 to 2009 only saw a further 1% reduction on average. On the whole, this is evidence supporting a stabilization in the Denver markets. Many neighborhoods saw a sales price increase over the summer, making 2008 a more stable environment, especially once compared with national trends.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Denver Neighborhoods: What's happened:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;Several neighborhoods actually showed an increase in sales. Those are:&#xD;&#xB7; Bonnie Brae/Belcaro&#xD;&#xB7; City Park&#xD;&#xB7; Country Club&#xD;&#xB7; Harvard Park&#xD;&#xB7; Hilltop&#xD;&#xB7; Observatory Park&#xD;&#xB7; Platt Park&#xD;&#xB7; Potter Highlands&#xD;&#xB7; Southern Hills&#xD;&#xB7; East Wash Park&#xD;&#xB7; Witter &#xD;&#xD;The following neighborhoods saw an increase in price per square foot:&#xD;&#xB7; City Park&#xD;&#xB7; Congress Park&#xD;&#xB7; Country Club North&#xD;&#xB7; DU&#xD;&#xB7; Platt Park&#xD;&#xB7; Potter Highlands&#xD;&#xB7; West Wash Park&#xD;&#xB7; Witter&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Tax Season is Coming Up! A Few Things to Keep In Mind&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;This year, the Federal Government has added some incentives to new and existing home owners that will help you out when you files your taxes this year.&#xD;&#xD;1.&#xA0; There are expanded tax credits if you have made your home more energy efficient.&#xA0; Seek out an accountant for more information about if your home improvement project can qualify.&#xD;&#xD;2.&#xA0; If you purchased a home for the first time in 2009 or haven't owned a home in the last three years, you are eligible for an $8,000 tax credit.&#xA0; It only has to be paid back if you stop using the home as your principal residence within three years of purchase.&#xD;&#xD;3.&#xA0; Congress also added a credit for long-time homeowners who purchase a new principal residence &#x2014; $6,500. To qualify, a homebuyer would have had to live at least five years in a previously owned home.&#xA0; Additionally, there are income limitations for both of these credits.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Ten Best US Cities to Buy:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;According to Realtor Magazine, the following US cities were chosed by economists at the most likely places to see increases in home prices over the next five years. They represent the best places to buy now: &#xD;&#xD;1.&#xA0; Boston-Cambridge, Mass. &#xD;2.&#xA0; Charlotte-Concord, N.C.-S.C. &#xD;3.&#xA0; Chicago-Joliet, Ill.-Wis. &#xD;4.&#xA0; Cincinnati-Middletown, Ohio&#xD;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;5.&#xA0; Denver-Aurora-Broomfield, Colorado&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &#xD;6.&#xA0; Minneapolis-St. Paul, Minn.&#xD;7.&#xA0; Philadelphia-Camden, Pa.-N.J&#xD;8.&#xA0; Portland-Vancouver-Beaverton, Ore.-Wash. &#xD;9.&#xA0; San Francisco-Oakland-Fremont, Calif. &#xD;10.&#xA0; Washington-Arlington-Alexandria, D.C.-Va.-Md.-W.V. &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Elizabeth Sacerdoti&#x2028;&lt;/b&gt;Fuller Sotheby's International Realty&#x2028;3033 East First Avenue, Suite 500 Denver, CO, 80206&#x2028;p:-303-501-3337&#x2028;&lt;a href="http://www.FullerSothebysRealty.com"&gt;www.FullerSothebysRealty.com&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
