<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:51:46 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;March Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_March_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Monday, March 1, 2010</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>March Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Dear Friends,&#xD;&#xD;This has been an exciting and rewarding year in the industry for me as I have grown my network of current and future clients.&#xA0; I have devoted myself to becoming the best possible advocate for my clients.&#xA0; From exploring every possible negotiating strategy to walking you through the intricacies of every document before you sign it, it is my goal to provide every home buyer or seller the best possible service for a lifetime.&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;However, you may not know that I've decided to keep my business 100% referral based.&#xA0; This means that I must provide excellent service and results all of the time in order to succeed.&#xA0; Instead of spending 50% of my time searching out the next client, I devote 100% of my time to&#xA0;working for my clients to get their deal to the closing table.&#xD;&#xD;This also means that I need your help.&#xA0; According the the National Association of Realtors, most people know between 6-10 people a year considering a real estate move.&#xA0; I ask that if and when you hear a friend or family member talk about real estate, you'll refer them to me and allow me to interview for the job.&#xA0; I promise I will provide them the best service because I know that I can add value to the people you care about's experiences with real estate.&#xA0; The benefit to you lies in knowing those people will always be taken care of by me.&#xA0; Thanks in advance for your support.&#xD;&#xD;Warmly,&#xD;Elizabeth&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;After the Closing Table:&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;Saving up for a down payment can be difficult, but you need to remember to keep a little nest egg on the side to cover any home improvement projects or surprise expenses.&#xA0; I recommended between 1-3% of the purchase price set aside for these purchases.&#xA0; Keep in mind, you will have a very good idea about potential costs from the home inspection conducted before you finalize your home purchase. This is why I always counsel buyers to be present at the time of inspection so they feel comfortable discussing potential issues with the inspector directly.&#xA0;&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;On the other side of the transaction, I frequently recommend that sellers have an inspection completed before they decide to list their home.&#xA0; This gives them the chance to address issues ahead of time. &#xA0;It will also give potential buyers of your home a feeling of security that you have acted in good faith on the property and addressed problems before they become an impediment to a sale.&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;To Refinance or Not to Refinance:&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;Market conditions indicate that now may be the perfect time to refinance.&#xA0; If this is something you've been toying with, consider starting the process now.&#xA0; A few things to consider:&#xD;&lt;b&gt;1.&lt;/b&gt;&#xA0; &lt;b&gt;Interest rates are hovering around 5%&lt;/b&gt; right now.&#xA0; Depending on your situation, if your interest rate is between .5 - 1% higher than this, it may be worthwhile to refinance.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;2.&lt;/b&gt;&#xA0; Low fixed interest rates &lt;b&gt;make converting from an adjustable rate loan into a fixed 15- or 30-year loan a smart move&lt;/b&gt;. Even if the adjustable payment is currently lower than a fixed rate payment, when rates rise again the monthly payment on an adjustable rate loan will quickly leapfrog a fixed rate loan.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;3.&lt;/b&gt; The current difference between fixed 15-year and 30-year interest rates is significant, making &lt;b&gt;refinancing into a shorter-term loan a compelling opportunity&lt;/b&gt;. This can save hundreds of thousands of dollars over the life of a loan and shorten the time to payoff , often with only a slight increase in your monthly payment.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;4.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;FHA efficiency mortgages provide consumers with an opportunity to refinance into a loan that will help pay for home efficiency improvements&lt;/b&gt;. These loans are meant to provide consumers with a way to make energy efficient improvements to their home as part of an origination or refinancing.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;5.&lt;/b&gt; Those homeowners whose equity situation has steadily deteriorated, leaving them with little, no or negative equity in their homes, should ask their lender or broker for help. Most have some flexibility with &lt;b&gt;government programs aimed at reducing rates for homeowners in weak equity positions.&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Colorado Real Estate Facts: A Brief Look at the Real Estate Market&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;(Information provided by the Colorado Association of Realtors)&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;1.&#xA0;&#xA0; Nearly three quarters of Colorado's 4.9 million residents are homeowners.&#xD;&#xD;2.&#xA0; &#xA0;59,156 Single Family Units were sold in 2009, a decrease of 12 percent compared to 2008. 13,258 Condos/Townhomes in 2009 were sold, a decrease of 13 percent compared to 2008.&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;3.&#xA0; &#xA0;The median price for single family homes was $214,584 for 2009, a five percent decrease from 2008. The median price for condos/townhomes was $150,333 for 2009, an 18 percent decrease from 2008.&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;4.&#xA0;&#xA0; Thirty-nine percent of recent home buyers were first-time buyers.&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;5.&#xA0; The typical first-time home buyer was 29 years old, while the typical repeat buyer was 47 years old. &#xD;&#xD;6. &#xA0;The median income was $58,200 among first-time buyers and $83,900 among repeat buyers. &#xD;&#xD;7. Twenty-one percent of recent home buyers were single females, and 9 percent were single males.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;New IPhone App!&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xA0;&#xD;Check out Realtor.Com's new iphone app.&#xA0; Definitely one of the best real estate apps out there, this app will allow you to find homes for sale near your current location, see photos and information as well as pinpoint nearby open houses.&#xA0; Check it out!&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Elizabeth Sacerdoti&#x2028;&lt;/b&gt;Fuller Sotheby's International Realty&#x2028;3033 East First Avenue, Suite 500 Denver, CO, 80206&#x2028;p:-303-501-3337&#x2028;&lt;a href="http://www.FullerSothebysRealty.com"&gt;www.FullerSothebysRealty.com&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
