<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:51:53 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;September Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_September_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Wednesday, September 1, 2010</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;September Real Estate Update&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Farewell, McMansion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The age of the McMansion is officially over. &#xA0;For the first time in a long time, the average American home size is actually getting smaller. &#xA0;Great news for the environment as less space also means fewer materials, less cost and a smaller overall footprint. &#xA0;In light of the recession, more people either stayed in their existing home or made renovations that rendered them more functional. &#xA0;As &#xA0;result, people have begun to realize that perhaps they don&#x2019;t really need 5,000 square feet. &#xA0;I always make a point of encouraging buyers to see rooms in a variety of ways, so that as their needs change, changing the use of spaces may allow them to remain functional. &#xA0;New construction homes that have 4-5 &#x201C;reading nooks&#x201D; with no real usable space are on their way out. The new median home size is 2,135 square feet in 2009 according to the census bureau and CNN Money. &#xA0;This is a drop from 2,300 square feet earlier in the decade. &#xA0;A possible explanation is a trend towards more multi-functioning space and less single purpose rooms, like the media room...(see below)&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Market in Review&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;The news is mixed on real estate today. Statistics are all pointing in different directions and every article I read tells a different story. &#xA0;The bottom line is that, YES, home prices have increased 3.6% over last year. &#xA0;However home sales plummeted 27% after the tax credit expired. &#xA0;In Denver, many neighborhoods saw an increase in price per square foot from 2009 (see last month&#x2019;s update), but fewer home sales over a 12-month period. &#xA0;On the front line of real estate, I can tell you that homes in perfect show condition and that are priced well are selling, sometimes with multiple offers. I recently sold a home after recieving 4 offers, 2 of which came in the same day after 7 weeks on the market. &#xA0;Buyers are out there, but they have certainly developed a more skilled knowledge base about the industry and are extremely well informed. &#xA0;Buyers are questioning the investment element of real estate in as much detail as they are thinking about the house itself. &#xA0;Although it may mean a lean year for real estate, personally, I like to think that the media&#x2019;s intense scrutiny on real estate will mean an increasingly informed public for many years to come. &#xA0;That can only be better for the industry.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Is your city over-priced or under-priced?&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;Take a look at Case-Schiller&#x2019;s home price index published on Tuesday regarding market changes over last year:&#xD;&lt;a href="http://money.cnn.com/real_estate/storysupplement/overvalued_cities/"&gt;http://money.cnn.com/real_estate/storysupplement/overvalued_cities/&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Buy Airconditioning, Seriously. &lt;/b&gt;&#xD;Appliances are a big deal. &#xA0;Today, almost 90% of new homes have air conditioning. &#xA0;63% of all existing homes having a cooling system. &#xA0;Only a decade ago, this number was closer to 50%, which indicates that buyers want to see those upgrades in your house. &#xA0;This trend is further exemplified by increases across the board from items ranging from garbage disposals to dishwashers. &#xA0;Your kitchen has always been a great place to invest in your home, but every-day conveniences are a must. &#xA0;Also note, the federal government rebate program has made many energy star appliances more affordable than ever!&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Interest Rates- 40 year low!&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;It's hard to imagine they've dipped lower, but interest rates are lower now than at any point &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;in the last 40 year&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;s.&#xA0;Buyers, you purchasing power has never been higher! &#xA0;Homeowners, if you haven't refinanced in the last 3 years, you should! &#xA0;Interest rates are hovering around 4.25%.</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
