<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:52:07 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;August Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="1_August_2011_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Monday, August 1, 2011</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>August 2011 Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;My newest downtown listing is an absolute gem!&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;This contemporary urban retreat offers the best of downtown living. &#xA0;Featuring fresh paint and carpet, hardwood floors, a spacious master suite and a west facing balcony with views of the mountains and downtown. &#xA0;At 1,197 square feet, this two bedroom 2 bath home will not last long! &#xA0;&#xA0;Priced at $250,000.  Located in North Capitol Hill.&#xD;See More Photos: &lt;a href="http://www.spotlighthometours.com/tours/tour.php?&amp;tourid=29111&amp;CFID=1148287&amp;CFTOKEN=26544694"&gt;1727 Pearl Street Photos and Tour&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Unbelievable Deal in Madison, WI&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;i&gt;To all my Wisconsin viewers&lt;/i&gt;- this darling townhome in Madison must sell and is being offered at a incredible price.  With 2 beds, 2.5 baths, this 1,170 square foot home has all the privacy you need in a great location on the west side.  There&#x2019;s also a 2 car garage and a private entry.  &#xD;Offered at $99,000&#xD;&#xD;For More Info: &lt;a href="http://SCWMLS.fnismls.com/publink/default.aspx?GUID=8b8f12f3-a150-4a6b-b2f2-8b7914453d67&amp;Report=Yes"&gt;6949 Chester Drive Photos and Info&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Denver is 4th for Oil and Gas Professionals&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Rigzone.com reports that Denver/Boulder is the 4th among up and coming energy cities for oil and gas professionals.  The study asked to consider quality of life, weather, professional conditions and appeal.  Denver was the only city in the United States to make the list, Dubai, Calgary and Rio de Janeiro rounded out the top three.  Positive reports among major industries in our city will only reflect positive long term news for our housing market as well.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;The Denver Market in Review&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Home sales continue to exceed new inventory for both condos and single family homes, which has led prices slightly upward- more so for single family homes.  Days on market remains unchanged as well- hovering between 117-156 for homes and 145-200 for condos.  This also means that most homes on the market- around 46%-  experience a price drop before they sell.  As a result, competitive pricing and remaining ahead of the market are critical to selling quickly.  Nationally, home prices just announced a 4.5% fall, however, some neighborhoods, especially in urban Denver neighborhoods remain hot.   In fact, the number of homes placed under contract in May and June rose 23% over last year.  &#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Check out the newest Sotheby&#x2019;s Denver listings in a digital version of our magazine, Connoisseur:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.americanwebinc.com/AW_Flip_Books/CONNOISSEUR/June_2011/index.html"&gt;http://www.americanwebinc.com/AW_Flip_Books/CONNOISSEUR/June_2011/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Fuller Sotheby&#x2019;s International Realty Neighborhood Report:&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Denver-Metro FSIR Half-Year 2011 Micro Market Report </richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
