<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:51:50 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;June Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Tuesday, June 1, 2010</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>June Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;New Format for Real Estate Update&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Dear All, &#xD;Since the launch of my website, I&#x2019;ve decided that linking you to this page would be the most effective way for you to see my e-newsletter.  I hope you enjoy this format better and of course, please keep your questions or interesting articles coming, I love being as knowledgeable as possible about everything related to real estate.  Thanks again and have a great June.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;New Listing in Green Mountain Village&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Check out my latest listing in Lakewood.  This 3 bed, 3 bath home has over 1900 Square feet and sits on a gorgeous lot minutes away from Green Mountain and some incredible mountain biking.  The home has fresh paint, newer eco-friendly floors, and tons of upgrades.  The kitchen has slab granite and a pass-through to the living room.  The master bedroom is large with an updated en-suite bath.  Please check out this house.  It is move-in ready and priced to sell quickly.  Here&#x2019;s a link with more information: &#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.spotlighthometours.com/us/22425"&gt;Home Tour of 1277 South Yank Court&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;                        &#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Lending News: Hold off on the new car&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Lenders are now pulling credit scores very close to the day of closing.  As a result, if there is a change in the debt to income ratio due to a large purchase made prior to closing, it could jeopardize your ability to close on the home.  Be careful and always speak to your realtor and lender if you are worried about this issue or have questions.&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Quality of Life in your City&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Recently, a friend, PJ Hoberman, sent me this interesting website that includes stats on how various US cities stack up against each other in a number of categories on quality of life.  I found it so interesting I wanted to pass it on.  Denver, naturally, does very well in all categories.  Thanks PJ for passing it on.&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.portfolio.com/interactive-features/2010/05/2010-Quality-of-Life-Major-Markets"&gt;Portfolio.com: Big City, Good Life&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;What&#x2019;s Going on with the Market?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Well, the preliminary results are in and even though the home purchase tax credit has ended, we&#x2019;ve still seen lots of activity.  My company is up in production about 50% over last year this time due to the incredible mortgage rates and inventory out there.  I did notice a price drop in many homes in the aftermath of the expiration of the tax credit, but things are definitely moving along and great properties don&#x2019;t last long.  The market is balancing out in Denver, and realtors in general are working harder and longer to get deals to close due to tightened lending laws and inspections, but in the long run, it will only be a benefit to the consumer.&#xD;&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
