<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:52:12 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;May Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="10_May_2012_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Thursday, May 10, 2012</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>May 2012 Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;What?  A Bidding War you say?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The market has moved so fast in the last month its hard for both buyers and sellers to believe.  The role of the agent managing the expectations and disappointments of this process can have added challenges.  Back in the days of the slower market, it used to be that maximizing your clients best possible price allowed most realtors to be hero&#x2019;s.  You could get unbelievable prices on a home for your buyer, and just getting something sold at all was a minor victory in a slow moving market.  Today, most brokers will tell you that keeping the deal together is a very challenging process.  and getting your client the house is often the best victory you can hope for.  Denver is a little ahead of this curve and not all cities are experiences our fast pace, but I suspect that many will soon.  Have a good solid plan of attack if you&#x2019;re thinking about buying soon- and that includes bringing a checkbook with you- many of these houses are going under contract within hours of hitting the MLS!  If you&#x2019;re thinking about selling- you should probably do it NOW.  As in, right now.  Seriously....&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Meet my Team!&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Check out a new tab at the top of my website: Your Neighborhood Experts.  This is a team project I&#x2019;m working on with two incredible real estate agents that I work with regularly, Pam Coakley and Catherine Carpenter!&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;First Quarter Sales Data- How is your Neighborhood Doing this year?&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Real Estate Quiz&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Sent by a great friend in California, I thought this was something you might enjoy from the Wall Street Journal:&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://projects.wsj.com/quiz/index.php?uid=challenge120427&amp;type=realestate&amp;mod=e2tw"&gt;How Well do you Know Luxury Real Estate?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;Denver is #2 in Nation for Quick Sales!&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;The Denver Post has some great information on how our real estate environment has changed in the last few months.  If you&#x2019;d like a little light reading, check out this article:&#xD;&lt;a href="http://www.denverpost.com/business/ci_20429074/denver-housing-market-second-nation-quick-sales?source=email"&gt;Denver Post on Real Estate Sales&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Financing a Condo, Here I go again...&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;Selling or buying a condominium has added challenges with restrictions on the kind of financing available.  However, never has it been harder for sellers to sell when federal guidelines often punish small developments and prevent any buyer from getting a loan.  If, for example, you live in a small building and one person owns even 2 units- this might make even a traditional conventional loan a virtual impossibility if one owner has a larger than 10-20% share in the building.  As these types of buildings are pervasive around Denver, I&#x2019;m adopting new strategies to ensure that the perfect buyer actually CAN buyer your unit.  It all begins and ends with a condo questionnaire.  Making sure this document is reviewed by a lender can tell you a lot about your property and I believe it now falls on agents to add this step to the initial listing process.  Never before has this raised as many problems as it does now, but this tiny step can save you months of headaches!&#xD;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
