<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="497EA2E1-56EC-4799-BAAF-D11A377D9038">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120814" date="2012-08-15 02:51:55 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;i&gt;January Real Estate Update&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="10_January_Real_Estate_Update_files/shapeimage_2.png" left="0px" top="0px" width="400px" height="300px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Monday, January 10, 2011</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>January Real Estate Update</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;What&#x2019;s in store for 2011?&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;The chief economist for the National Association of Realtors has announced that in 2011 consumers can, &#x201C;Expect higher mortgage rates, relatively flat home prices and a rebound in home sales.&#x201D; &#xA0;Furthermore, a recovery would lead to a drop in foreclosures, which have run at about 2 million a year the past two years versus 400,000 a year in previous periods.&#xD;Affordability is also in the market's favor. The monthly mortgage payment on the median-priced metro-Denver home is $257 less than it was in the second quarter of 2005. &#xA0;Tighter underwriting standards have resulted in fewer new loans going bad, making 2010 the best "vintage" for mortgages ever at the Federal Housing Administration, according the National Association of Realtors. &#xA0;That strong performance might encourage lenders to loosen up a little more and qualify potential buyers now blocked out of the market. &#xA0;The forecast calls for mortgage rates, which briefly approached 4 percent, to return to 5 percent next year and 5.9 percent in 2012 as inflationary pressures build in the economy. &#xA0;Bottom line, despite a drop in home sales in December, most market analysts are expecting good things to come in the months ahead.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;2011: New Colorado Contracts&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;If you&#x2019;ve ever bought or sold real estate in Colorado, starting January 1st, expect to see a totally different real estate contract. &#xA0;In an attempt to simply contracts for consumers, the Colorado Real Estate Commission is introducing contracts geared towards specific property types. &#xA0;Instead of wondering why you&#x2019;re checking a box indicating you don&#x2019;t have any growing &#xA0;crops in your condominium, the five new contracts will be much better suited to your specific property type.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Mortgages:&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;According to a new Lending Tree survey, while a overwhelming 96 percent of American consumers compare prices when shopping for almost anything, nearly 40 percent obtain just one home loan quote. &#xA0;Though it is a decision that will affect them for the next 15-30 years, nearly three-quarters (72 percent) of homeowners spent the equivalent of a full working day or less shopping for their home loan. &#xA0;With less than one percent affecting your monthly payment by an average $100, consider spending the time to investigating a wide array of choices. &#xA0;Not all loans are created equal! &#xA0;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Finally...&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;Wishing you all a wonderful start to 2011! &#xA0;Thanks to many of you for the business and referrals over the past year. &#xA0;Happy Holidays, &#xA0;Elizabeth</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
